<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mavlink>
  <!-- XML file for prototyping definitions for standard.xml  -->
  <include>standard.xml</include>
  <version>0</version>
  <dialect>0</dialect>
  <enums>
    <enum name="AIRSPEED_SENSOR_FLAGS" bitmask="true">
      <description>Airspeed sensor flags</description>
      <entry value="0" name="AIRSPEED_SENSOR_UNHEALTHY">
        <description>Airspeed sensor is unhealthy</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="1" name="AIRSPEED_SENSOR_USING">
        <description>True if the data from this sensor is being actively used by the flight controller for guidance, navigation or control.</description>
      </entry>
    </enum>
    <enum name="RADIO_RC_CHANNELS_FLAGS" bitmask="true">
      <description>RADIO_RC_CHANNELS flags (bitmask).</description>
      <entry value="1" name="RADIO_RC_CHANNELS_FLAGS_FAILSAFE">
        <description>Failsafe is active.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="2" name="RADIO_RC_CHANNELS_FLAGS_FRAME_MISSED">
        <description>Indicates that the current frame has not been received. Channel values are frozen.</description>
      </entry>
    </enum>
  </enums>
  <messages>
    <message id="53" name="MISSION_CHECKSUM">
      <description>Checksum for the current mission, rally point or geofence plan, or for the "combined" plan (a GCS can use these checksums to determine if it has matching plans).
        This message must be broadcast with the appropriate checksum following any change to a mission, geofence or rally point definition
        (immediately after the MISSION_ACK that completes the upload sequence).
        It may also be requested using MAV_CMD_REQUEST_MESSAGE, where param 2 indicates the plan type for which the checksum is required.
        The checksum must be calculated on the autopilot, but may also be calculated by the GCS.
        The checksum uses the same CRC32 algorithm as MAVLink FTP (https://mavlink.io/en/services/ftp.html#crc32-implementation).
        The checksum for a mission, geofence or rally point definition is run over each item in the plan in seq order (excluding the home location if present in the plan), and covers the following fields (in order):
        frame, command, autocontinue, param1, param2, param3, param4, param5, param6, param7.
        The checksum for the whole plan (MAV_MISSION_TYPE_ALL) is calculated using the same approach, running over each sub-plan in the following order: mission, geofence then rally point.
      </description>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="mission_type" enum="MAV_MISSION_TYPE">Mission type.</field>
      <field type="uint32_t" name="checksum">CRC32 checksum of current plan for specified type.</field>
    </message>
    <message id="295" name="AIRSPEED">
      <description>Airspeed information from a sensor.</description>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="id" instance="true">Sensor ID.</field>
      <field type="float" name="airspeed" units="m/s">Calibrated airspeed (CAS).</field>
      <field type="int16_t" name="temperature" units="cdegC">Temperature. INT16_MAX for value unknown/not supplied.</field>
      <field type="float" name="raw_press" units="hPa">Raw differential pressure. NaN for value unknown/not supplied.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="flags" enum="AIRSPEED_SENSOR_FLAGS">Airspeed sensor flags.</field>
    </message>
    <message id="420" name="RADIO_RC_CHANNELS">
      <description>Radio channels. Supports up to 32 channels. Channel values are in centered 13 bit format. Range is [-4096,4096], center is 0. Conversion to PWM is x * 5/32 + 1500.  
		The target_system field should normally be set to the system id of system the radio receiver is connected to, the target_component field can be normally set to 0. 
		</description>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="target_system">System ID (can be 0 for broadcast, but this is discouraged).</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="target_component">Component ID (normally 0 for broadcast).</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="count">Total number of RC channels being received. This can be larger than 24, indicating that more channels are available but not given in this message.</field>
      <field type="uint16_t" name="flags" enum="RADIO_RC_CHANNELS_FLAGS" display="bitmask">Radio rc channels status flags.</field>
      <extensions/>
      <field type="int16_t[32]" name="channels">RC channels. Channels above count should be set to 0, to benefit from MAVLink's zero padding.</field>
    </message>
  </messages>
</mavlink>
