<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mavlink>
  <include>development.xml</include>
  <version>0</version>
  <dialect>0</dialect>
  <enums>
    <!-- The MAV_CMD enum entries describe either: -->
    <!--  * the data payload of mission items (as used in the MISSION_ITEM_INT message) -->
    <!--  * the data payload of mavlink commands (as used in the COMMAND_INT and COMMAND_LONG messages) -->
    <!-- ALL the entries in the MAV_CMD enum have a maximum of 7 parameters -->
    <enum name="MAV_CMD">
      <description>Commands to be executed by the MAV. They can be executed on user request, or as part of a mission script. If the action is used in a mission, the parameter mapping to the waypoint/mission message is as follows: Param 1, Param 2, Param 3, Param 4, X: Param 5, Y:Param 6, Z:Param 7. This command list is similar what ARINC 424 is for commercial aircraft: A data format how to interpret waypoint/mission data. NaN and INT32_MAX may be used in float/integer params (respectively) to indicate optional/default values (e.g. to use the component's current yaw or latitude rather than a specific value). See https://mavlink.io/en/guide/xml_schema.html#MAV_CMD for information about the structure of the MAV_CMD entries</description>
      <entry value="199" name="MAV_CMD_SET_POI_FOCUS" hasLocation="false" isDestination="false">
        <description>Sets a POI at the current focus point of the camera frame. This assumes that the camera system has the ability to geo-locate the current focus point.</description>
        <param index="1" label="Operation mode" minValue="0" maxValue="1" increment="1">Operation mode. 0 = set POI at current location; 1 = set POI at current location and track it.</param>
        <param index="2" label="X Position in the camera frame" minValue="0" increment="1">Position given by the number of pixels in X direction of the camera frame. Origin on the bottom left corner of the camera frame.</param>
        <param index="3" label="Y Position in the camera frame" minValue="0" increment="1">Position given by the number of pixels in Y direction of the camera frame. Origin on the bottom left corner of the camera frame.</param>
      </entry>
    </enum>
    <enum name="POI_GEOMETRY_TYPE">
      <description>Point-of-Interest geometry types.</description>
      <entry value="0" name="POI_GEOMETRY_TYPE_UNKNOWN">
        <description>Unknown geometry.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="1" name="POI_GEOMETRY_TYPE_SQUARE">
        <description>Square.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="2" name="POI_GEOMETRY_TYPE_RECTANGLE">
        <description>Rectangle.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="3" name="POI_GEOMETRY_TYPE_CIRCLE">
        <description>Circle.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="4" name="POI_GEOMETRY_TYPE_CUBE">
        <description>Cube.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="5" name="POI_GEOMETRY_TYPE_CUBOID">
        <description>Cuboid.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="6" name="POI_GEOMETRY_TYPE_SPHERE">
        <description>Sphere.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="7" name="POI_GEOMETRY_TYPE_CYLINDER">
        <description>Cylinder.</description>
      </entry>
    </enum>
    <enum name="POI_CLASSIFICATION">
      <description>
        Point-of-Interest classification.
        Provides default classes (0 to 2147483647 reserved), but implementation-specific classes can be considered instead on the field where the classification is set.
      </description>
      <entry value="0" name="POI_CLASSIFICATION_UNKNOWN">
        <description>Unknown classification.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="1" name="POI_CLASSIFICATION_GEO_MARKER">
        <description>Geolocation marker.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="2" name="POI_CLASSIFICATION_LANDING_PAD">
        <description>Landing pad.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="3" name="POI_CLASSIFICATION_CLEAR_LANDING_SPOT">
        <description>Detected suited landing spot.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="4" name="POI_CLASSIFICATION_BUILDING">
        <description>Building.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="5" name="POI_CLASSIFICATION_PERSON">
        <description>Person.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="6" name="POI_CLASSIFICATION_VEHICLE">
        <description>Vehicle.</description>
      </entry>
      <entry value="7" name="POI_CLASSIFICATION_INGRESS_PORTAL">
        <description>Ingress portal.</description>
      </entry>
    </enum>
  </enums>
  <messages>
    <message id="238" name="POI_REPORT">
      <wip/>
      <!-- This message is work-in-progress and it can therefore change. It should NOT be used in stable production environments. -->
      <description>Reports information for a detected Point-of-Interest (POI).
        This can be either set by an operator (through MAV_CMD_SET_POI_FOCUS) or through onboard software or external processes.
        The receiving system should track the POI being reported based on its UID + time of detection + time of update.
        Detection time happens once for the same UID, while time of update changes when a specific metadata of that POI gets changed (e.g. position).
        The time of update should be changed on the sending system, based on the determined data in regards to that specific POI.
        So, POIs that are received again should be updated if the time of update has changed.
        Note: The sending system should repeat the current POIs at a fixed default rate of 2Hz to keep the protocol stateless). The fixed rate though can be set by the receiver using MAV_CMD_SET_MESSAGE_INTERVAL, which is advised for POIs that are not static or for which the state updates are high - decision on the rates of some specific POIs is at the implementers consideration.
      </description>
      <field type="uint32_t" name="time_boot_ms" units="ms">Timestamp (time since system boot).</field>
      <field type="uint64_t" name="time_utc_detected" units="ms" invalid="0">Timestamp (time since UNIX epoch) of the POI detection, in UTC. 0 for unknown.</field>
      <field type="uint64_t" name="time_utc_updated" units="ms" invalid="0">Timestamp (time since UNIX epoch) of the last POI update, in UTC. 0 for unknown.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="confidence_overall" units="%" invalid="UINT8_MAX">Generic confidence level. 0..100, UINT8_MAX when unknown.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="confidence_detection" units="%" invalid="UINT8_MAX">Confidence level of the POI detection. 0..100, UINT8_MAX when unknown.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="confidence_classification" units="%" invalid="UINT8_MAX">Confidence level of the POI classification. 0..100, UINT8_MAX when unknown.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="confidence_localization" units="%" invalid="UINT8_MAX">Confidence level of the POI localization. 0..100, UINT8_MAX when unknown.</field>
      <field type="uint16_t" name="ttl" units="s">Time to live: If this time has elapsed, the POI should be deleted on the receiver side. A value of 0 should indicate no timeout.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="flags" display="bitmask">Bitmask for POI state. Bit 1: POI is in focus on camera, Bit 8: POI has been cleared and should be deleted</field>
      <field type="uint64_t" name="uid" invalid="0">Unique ID for a given POI. Updates to a POIs information should use the same uid. 0 means unknown.</field>
      <field type="int32_t" name="latitude" units="degE7" invalid="0">Latitude (WGS84) of the POI. If unknown: 0 (both Lat/Lon).</field>
      <field type="int32_t" name="longitude" units="degE7" invalid="0">Longitude (WGS84) of the POI. If unknown: 0 (both Lat/Lon).</field>
      <field type="int32_t" name="alt_amsl" units="mm" invalid="INT32_MAX">Altitude AMSL of the POI. Positive for up. INT32_MAX if unknown.</field>
      <field type="int32_t" name="alt_elep" units="mm" invalid="INT32_MAX">Altitude above the EGM96 ellipsoid of the POI. Positive for up. INT32_MAX if unknown.</field>
      <field type="uint32_t" name="classification" enum="POI_CLASSIFICATION">Classification of the POI. Can either used the POI_CLASSIFICATION enumeration (0x0 - 0x7FFFFFFF reserved), or use the reserved range for implementation specific (0x80000000 - UINT32_MAX).</field>
      <field type="float" name="x" units="m" invalid="NaN">X position of the POI in the NED frame. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="float" name="y" units="m" invalid="NaN">Y position of the POI in the NED frame. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="float" name="z" units="m" invalid="NaN">Z position of the POI in the NED frame. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="float[4]" name="q" invalid="[0]">Orientation quaternion (w, x, y, z order) of the POI in the NED frame. Zero-rotation is 1, 0, 0, 0. Unknown is 0, 0, 0, 0.</field>
      <field type="float" name="dist" units="m" invalid="NaN">Distance from the aircraft sensor/camera focal point to the POI. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="float" name="vel_n" units="m/s" invalid="NaN">North velocity of the POI. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="float" name="vel_e" units="m/s" invalid="NaN">East velocity of the POI. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="float" name="vel_d" units="m/s" invalid="NaN">Down velocity of the POI. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="float" name="hdg" units="rad" invalid="NaN">Heading of the POI in the NED frame. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="float" name="height" units="m" invalid="NaN">Height of the POI shape. When the geometry is a circle, sphere or cylinder, represents the radius. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="float" name="width" units="m" invalid="NaN">Width of the POI shape. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="float" name="depth" units="m" invalid="NaN">Depth of the POI shape. NAN if unknown.</field>
      <field type="uint8_t" name="geometry" enum="POI_GEOMETRY_TYPE">POI geometry type.</field>
      <field type="float[3]" name="approach_vector_start" units="m" invalid="[NaN]">Recommended vector start point, in the NED frame, for vehicle approach to the POI. This can either be determined by the end system where the POI was detected ir by a system forwarding the information to another vehicle. Unknown is NaN, NaN, NaN.</field>
      <field type="float[3]" name="approach_vector_end" units="m" invalid="[NaN]">Recommended vector end point, in the NED frame, for vehicle approach to the POI. This can either be determined by the end system where the POI was detected ir by a system forwarding the information to another vehicle. Unknown is NaN, NaN, NaN.</field>
      <field type="float[3]" name="approach_velocity" units="m/s" invalid="[NaN]">Recommended NED velocity for vehicle approach to the POI. This can either be determined by the end system where the POI was detected ir by a system forwarding the information to another vehicle. Unknown is NaN, NaN, NaN.</field>
      <field type="char[32]" name="name">Name of the POI, if the system provides one. NULL terminated string.</field>
    </message>
  </messages>
</mavlink>
